this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at SC - radio dotnet SC radio is
brought to you by the I Triple E
Computer Society I Triple E software
magazine online at computer org slash
software
[Music]
developers are you ready it's time to
upgrade your data platform to inner
systems iris choose your language choose
your tools choose your environment
collaborate build faster and deploy more
efficiently when you can make faster
decisions there's no telling what you'll
create ready set code start coding for
free visit inner systems comm slash try
to try iris welcome to software
engineering radio I'm your host Gavin
Henry and today my guest is Burt Hubert
hello hi Bert and Bert has had a 20-year
track record in commercial and open
source software development is the
author of the open source powered DNS
name server which powers around 50% of
all Internet domain names in Europe
Bert is active in the IETF and works on
the standardization of DNS Bert welcome
to software engineering radio is there
anything I missed in your bio that you'd
like to add no this was good excellent
during the show we'll be talking about
DNS security in general with the second
half of the show talking about DNS over
HTTPS or more commonly known as do H
however I'd like to start with an
overview of DNS so what does DNS in its
basic form we used to be able to say
that look DNS is like the phonebook of
the Internet it's no longer working
because younger people have never seen a
phonebook so it's become easier to say
that the phonebook is like sort of DNS
of telephony whenever you you you type
in a name and the internet computers
cannot directly connect to names they
connect to IP addresses ipv4 ipv6 and
DNS sits between you and the IP
addresses whenever you want to connect
to a website your computer needs to look
up what is the IP address of that
website and DNS provides that and in
addition to that it's not just IP
addresses for website visits DNS also
tells you where the mail server for a
domain is located for example so without
DNS we like to summarize it offer a
parity in s that without DNS there is no
internet and if your DNS is slow
the Internet this is slow and if your
DNS is sort of working so-so than your
own Internet experience will be so-so
okay so what is the current protocol
what does it look like oh that's a good
question so it is an old protocol so the
first roots of DNS go back to like 1983
or something like that and it was
influenced by Pascal which is a
programming language was was sort of
popular in academia at the time and it
is a binary protocol so whenever you
look something up packet has to be
crafted and this packet contains the
query of course but it's not anything
you would recognize as JSON or as XML or
whatever it was written in a time when
every bit counted and they try to make
sure that almost every DNS message and
almost every DNS response fit within 512
bytes because that was the maximum
packet size that they thought they could
reasonably use and because of that there
is actually the protocol it's like fully
binary and domain names are for example
compressed internally so if you have a
DNS query that has a bunch of answers
than instead of repeating the names of
all those answers it will contain
pointers back to the original previous
answer so it is a binary protocol with
built-in compression and and you can
imagine how well that went because the
amount of DNS exploits and and crashing
burke's we have seen now for since 1983
has been like stunning so in short it is
a very old protocol that we rely on all
day long and it's tricky to get right so
I wouldn't class that as simple in
today's terms no no no it's it's
definitely not simple and and you see
for example that often it's married it's
miss messed up so for example DNS knows
the difference between this name does
not exist so let's say I want to go to
power DNS dot uk' and that name probably
does not exist and so that's one kind of
DNS error but there's a second DNS error
that says well the
name exists but it does not have an ipv6
address so that's a new ones beyond that
name exists or it doesn't exist
it says the name exists or the name does
exist but the thing you asked for does
not exist and many implementations will
mess up these two different outcomes for
example many load balancers even to this
day when they do DNS if you ask them for
the ipv6 address of a website they will
very frequently give the wrong answer so
they will answer the whole name you
asked for it does not exist they will
not say the ipv6 address does not exist
it will say no the whole name doesn't
exist and this this has in the past led
to like really big brand name websites
disappearing from the web because a big
load balancer messed up this kind of new
ones and they all did the DNS themselves
I take it yeah so for a very long time
people used to use the very good bind
name server for everything to the point
that when we started power DNS the only
way we could describe ourselves was as a
known bind name server so bind is the
notice this was not the first name
server and not by a long shot even but
like in the 1990s it was the only name
server around to the point that yeah we
had to describe ourselves as a known
bind name server recently people have
started to craft their own name server
things for all kinds of products and and
they have been doing a terrible job at
it it is a protocol that is fiendishly
difficult to get right so yeah it's not
simple and there's a lot of dubious code
out there do you mean when we say when
we called ourselves do you mean the
power DNS project yes so we got launched
somewhere in 1999 because someone wanted
to do geographical log balancing via DNS
so that American users would end up on
American servers and European users
would end up in European servers and
back in the late 1990s this was a very
very novel idea where people say yeah it
cannot be done it's impossible and and
what we did decide to do it and
and when we try to market our products
that we build the name server people
said yeah sorry so you shall bind I was
in our way we made our own name server
but there was such a strange concept at
the time that we in in our marketing we
just had to sell ourselves as a known
bind name server see talking about load
balancers and CD ends on show three four
seven we interviewed Daniel Corbett on
h8 proxy which I think discusses DNS
there and we also did show three four
five with Tyler McMullen on CDN networks
there for our listeners to review again
so if we take the usual scenario not not
server side but browser side you are I
go to our browser our choice to the
handful of choices nowadays you type in
the the website and then it does the DNS
lookup what you've explained already is
ipv4 ipv6 so that would be an a records
and a double a double a record is that
yeah we were actually called a quat a
record okay okay and because it's easier
to pronounce so it's actually the action
starts earlier then you say even as you
are typing a URL in the URL bar now that
we still have it but while you are
typing it DNS lookups are already being
made so we very often see these these
partial requests happening and then when
you finally hit enter then it's likely
that the DNS lookup has already
completed in the background and indeed
it does simultaneous ipv4 and ipv6
lookups and it will also then attempt to
simultaneously set up connections to the
ipv4 and ipv6 address and start working
on which chain finishes first so if the
ipv6 lookup end connection finished
first that's the server that will
actually get the request and this is the
so-called happy eyeballs principle and
it turns out that this days already is
complex enough to get right because
especially ipv6 and we love ipv6 very
much so more than our users are I would
say but ipv6 queries far far more often
than you'd like
back with errors for example so the the
correct answer is of course here is the
ipv6 address for the website the second
best answer is well the name exists but
it doesn't doesn't have an ipv6 address
but quite often you get back the answer
the whole name doesn't exist or you get
an actual error back to that lab we try
to resolve this name but yeah we got
timeouts and then work so quite a lot
happens behind the scenes to make DNS
work really well and that's important
because like I said if DNS is a bit slow
the whole browser feels slow so browsers
by now they do a lot of tricks to make
sure that they that their queries get
answers pronto because it really impacts
the user experience yeah sounds like
there's more than harmful DNS requests
going on as soon as even think about
going online with the browser yeah I did
if you look at the nest traffic that is
coming out of a typical household right
now and because of the the functions we
we fulfill at some of our deployments we
have statistics on how much DNS is
coming out of a household and that is a
typical household now generates I think
one DNS query per second or something
like that and and and that's about the
whole household by the way and then
apart from the a in quad-a records what
else do you typically see being stored
in DNS yeah so as mentioned before when
you do send out email the right mail
exchanger needs to be found so that's
so-called MX record and you see a lot of
DOS both on the the sending side so one
of the things that for example that that
we that you can do with DNS if you have
a network with millions of subscribers
on there and you're worrying about bad
behavior going on there like servers
that have been hacked and one of the
surest ways of finding if the server is
hacked is checking how many M X domain
queries it is doing because many servers
that have been hacked will furiously
starts attempted to spam the whole world
so then you see tons of MX records going
by and close seconds or they might even
be more important than or these more
frequent than MX records or so-called
text records so and text records were
just meant to be to store arbitrary
bits of text in DNS for whatever reason
and if you look what happens these text
records are now used by many spam lists
to where you can look up if this IP
address is known to be spamming or if
this domain name is known to be involved
in phishing so many mail servers will
perform a DNS text records lookups to
figure out if a sending a mail server is
actually known to be spammy or not and
it's interesting that DNS was used for
that technology because to this day DNS
with all its faults and all its age and
all its crypt that has grown on it it is
the one single technology that you can
with very limited investment say hey I
can make a worldwide distributed
database and you can ask it tens of
thousands of questions per second and
you'll get good answers and that's the
kind of thing you need for example when
you need two dozen lookups for every
email message you see so summarizing its
MX records and text records mostly yeah
I think it's a product of its time we're
similar to the routing protocol BGP
where they're both really good designs
and they were designed with the limited
bandwidth unlimited space so it really
did force your creativity yeah I would
have to agree the limitations at the
time were stark there are many things
that we would do differently right now
and also the expectations were different
so DNS for example relies on the
internet being a nice place so when you
ask DNS question this does not happen
usually over a tcp/ip connection it
happens over a UDP connection and a UDP
query is is just throwing out a packet
to a server so it does not set up a
connection it just sends a single packet
that's extremely efficient and then when
the response comes back that response is
contained in another packet and of
course as a client you would like to
verify that the packet that came back in
response is actually the right answer
that it was not a packet that was sent
by by anyone else you want to have a big
ID on there to
sure that the response matches the query
and and these days we insist on like 64
bits of security for that kind of thing
so that people don't randomly send
answers that might get accepted and it
turns out that in DNS on every query and
every response is a 16-bit a two byte
field and that's the field that tells
you that this answer is the right one
and that was fine at the time because
they said yeah that means that you need
to send thousands of packets if you want
to spoof in a fake answer and no one is
gonna send thousands of packets because
that they couldn't yeah they couldn't
imagine that happened and and these days
we can send a thousand packets in a
millisecond so it turned out that that
protection level at 16-bit protection
level that they put on there in 1983 is
completely inadequate by today's
standards it's like the outage who needs
more than was it team K or two Meg yeah
yeah and actually when you go back when
you ask people said why did you use only
16 bits of security and the answer was
sort of stunning this and oh we didn't
even mean it as security it was just a
sort of to make it more CPU efficient to
match the question to the answer they
didn't mean it as security and to make
things worse in the original
specification they also said well
because of the way computers work if you
send a question to name server with IP
address a you might get back an answer
from IP address B which we know as
spoofing we now see this as a
man-in-the-middle attack and the RFC at
the time helpfully the RFC is an
internet standard and the RFC helpfully
says well if you get an answer back from
the wrong IP address you should still
accept it and we cannot imagine and that
that anymore but on the other hand we
have to realize that we use the protocol
we were at least I wasn't around
designing internet standards in 1983
yeah it was a different world at the
time what types of DNS servers do we
have yeah so it's important to realize
that there are multiple kinds of name
servers so you have in you have a so
called authoritative name
servers and these are the ones that say
I know all about power DNS comm and this
is the IP address of WWE news comm so
these are authoritative servers that
know what they are talking about but
it's not enough to have an authoritative
server because I could anyone could
start a server that says I know
everything about power DNS calm but no
one would be able to find that server so
to solve this sort of chicken-and-egg
problem everything on the internet
starts with the root servers and these
are now I think over a thousand servers
with 26 I P addresses and you can always
ask a question of these 26 I P addresses
and you will you will get an answer it
might not be the answer you want but
it's that is an answer and this root
server is authoritative for the whole
internet so that's good I mean it sounds
nice I'm 34 the old Internet root
servers effectively don't know a lot but
they do know that if you ask a question
for power Deena's com
they know that well actually we don't
know the answer to that but we know that
the dot-com servers they know the answer
and you should ask them and then the
root server helpfully gives you a list
of IP addresses for the dot-com servers
and dot-com servers we can ask them we
can say hey dear dot-com Server what's
the IP address for power D nest of comb
and the.com server will again say well I
don't really know but I do know where
the power Dina's dot-com name servers
are and maybe you should ask over there
and here are their IP addresses and then
finally you end up with this
authoritative server that I started this
story with and that one can actually
tell you yeah this is the right IP
address okay so 26 I P addresses sounds
a bit familiar to something else that
has 26 things in it yeah and it is still
a lucky accident okay but I'll get to
that because it ties into the 512 byte
packet limit I meant translationally but
but now to find our way among all these
authoritative servers that that was
originally thought to be too much work
for simple computers so a separate
server was invented for that called a
resolver porrik
- and this resolver or cache that would
then traverse all these authoritative
servers starting from the root server to
find the answer to your actual question
and that is actually still the model
that we have so in your browser you type
the domain name you want to visit the
browser sends the query to that - it's
configured resolver that is part of your
local network typically and that one
will troll the old internet for you and
consult different authoritative servers
until it finds the right answer so the
resolvers come with a predefined list of
things yes this is the so-called hints
file and the hints file contained all
these contain a suggestion a list of
around 26 IP addresses and those that
list might be outdated might be that you
turn on your computer and it hasn't been
turned on for for a few years so let's
start up a resolving name server we'll
try all these so-called hints hints
records to see if it can find a name
server that answers and typically we see
that out of the sort of 13 ipv4 4 and 13
ipv6 records we see that one or two of
them changed every year so even if you
had not turned on your resolving name
server since the past 15 years
it would have found one IP address that
worked and from there it would have
learned the latest list of 26 I P
addresses that's pretty impressive I has
that longevity yeah I think that came
from a time when people realized that a
computer that you haven't done any
administration on for the past 10 years
is bound to be act by now and be
operated by a troupe of Russian hackers
that you don't know at the time they
thought it was very important that
machines that had not been had not seen
any maintenance for the past 10 years
would still work well and these 26
things I've read somewhere about K and a
and P yeah so they affectionately are
known as a root or B root or whatever C
root and they run from a root 2 m root
and each of them has a history where it
came from so
a root were sort of the yeah the
original root server of the internet and
today it is being operated by a very
sign and that used to be network
solutions that goes back into the dark
ages of the internet and for example F
roots is operated by the Internet
software consortium the people that also
make the bind name server and then k
roots is run by a ripe the European IP
address people so each of them has a
host and where it lives on NASA has one
and the Japanese ipv6 project has one
and that's not even not that long ago
these were actually these thirteen
servers were also actually physically
like thirteen servers that you could
visit so I visited the number of them
and it's sort of fun to sort of stand
next to one of the the roots of the
Internet but these days through the
miracles of any cast it has now become
possible to take a single IP address and
have it be served by hundreds of
computers all over the world and so I
haven't done run the latest numbers but
I would guess that if you physically
look at how many computers are doing
route surfing right now that is a number
that used to be like 13 and is now
probably closer to 1,000 or maybe even
2,000 yeah really just show you how
critical DNS is to the Internet I had
safeguarded by all these independent
companies yeah and I'm I'd like to move
us all a bit because we're running our
time a little bit so when we use the
recursos they have a list of pence in
their database and then they go and
validate that and speak to the route if
we talk about trust
how does power DNS techcom get into the
whole system you know how do you if you
forget the commercial side of buying it
but how does that get registered within
the core of the DNS and how does that
get trusted to just a semi brief answer
so we can move on
sure so so actually there is a whole
parallel network so we have the name
server the DNS protocol by which we ask
questions but if I want to get my name
registered at in the dot-com zone I will
have to convince a registrar
which is a company in between that I own
that domain and that they should publish
my changes and so this is actually we
have a downstream protocol that DNS of
once the data is out there you can ask
here is using DNS but if you want to
change DNS data there's a whole zoo of
protocols some of which are standardized
called EPP for example and and many of
them that are not standardized so
actually the whole authentication
business of how do I make changes to
publish domain names is far messier than
how do you actually send out queries and
how does the registrar prove who it is
to get into may name registers as it
were alright that's a really good one
and to be honest I don't really know
it's sort of interesting that I don't
know because that shows you how how big
the separation the gap is between the
people that serve DNS names which would
be my business and and how people
register domain names and I assume there
are blobs of XML which are being signed
with certificates and but to be honest I
don't know I look to fr business in the
UK to get registered with nomina and
it's quite a process it's like creating
a new business really you got to prove
that you've got a customer base that
you're trustworthy that you can do all
these things and I'm not surprised it's
something that you don't really know
about it unless you've tried to sell it
to me names yeah no but it's good that
it's somewhat difficult because the
people that are operating in their day
and they have the power to to register
domain names and change them on your
behalf because you make no mistake if
you record if you register your domain
name somewhere you can do all the
security that you want but the place
where you register the domain has full
control of your domain name and they
could change everything about it it is
crucial that you register your domain at
the right place exactly so our software
engineers
why is DNS so important to us when we're
writing internet-facing software it's
always sits between you and the client
and or if you are a client it's if it's
it's between you and the server and
unless you're really fond of typing in
IP addresses then then there is no
alternative you always have to
your stuff through DNS if you want it or
not and the interesting thing is that
actually being in the DNS world we are
rather fond of using IP addresses
because they always work so I recently
launched a project that has to connect
to servers and for the longest time I
did not actually support the nest
lookups in there I told people to
connect to fixed IP addresses and and
when that no longer scaled I I started
using DNS of course but there is sort of
a irony in there in it I come from this
my whole company is called DNS and we're
like well let's see how far we can get
without DNS but in general you will
always everything you do touches DNS and
if you want it or not so for example if
you look at the DNS queries that come
out of a typical enterprise you will see
all kinds of failed projects in their
old servers companies that have been
acquired and then stuff everything is
DNS so even if you want it and I'm not
saying it's great technology it's just
that your yeah it's very difficult to
not use it and now do you recommend that
anyone ever runs their own resolvers as
a software engineer authoritative DNS or
deep sub okay that a different team no I
in a typical enterprise situation you
had best say look there's no competitive
advantage for you to run your own
resolver is that it's really something
that your network provider provides and
it will not get better if you run your
own from an enterprise I think the
answer is is very different if you are
at home and you don't trust your
internet service provider but if you are
in a professional setting where you
don't trust your network you're probably
in the wrong place I see that might be
some of your touch on a day when we get
to the DNS over HTTPS okay so I like to
shift is a long event so now we've
covered what DNS is obviously you could
speak ours about more detail of what DNA
says but I think that's a good
foundation yeah we're good yeah I'd like
to discuss as many of the bad things
that we have time for that could be done
to it so you tell us a little bit about
DNS hijacking yeah so there are DNS is
vulnerable in a number of ways for being
hijacked but but the story is actually
slightly different than then you might
think it is possible to fake DNA
answers because the original DNS
protocol has no encryption on it no
authentication there's no integrity so
if you sit on the wire and you have the
ability to change packets you can just
invent your own DNS answers and and no
one will know this was typically seen as
very bad and of course it is very bad
but in reality turned out that it is
it's pretty difficult because if you are
the man in the middle you can already do
a lot of things and the main worry was
really not so much the man in the middle
but was the man on the side and by that
I mean that let's say I know that
someone someone's house they're watching
a lot of YouTube videos or whatever and
so I flood their house with answers to
the question what is the IP address of
youtube.com
I just keep sending packets that contain
the answer to the question of the IP
address for youtube.com is 1.2.3.4 and
then the idea was that eventually one
day my fake answer would be accepted and
your computer would connect to 1.2.3.4
and not the real YouTube server and in
practice it turned out that this on a
modern Internet this is extremely
difficult to do and has not been done a
lot in practice what has been done a lot
in practice and has been extremely
painful is where Dinah's gets hijacked
administratively
by which I mean we don't hack the
protocol we just move your whole domain
name to new servers and why has that
been so successful that turns out that
there has not been a tremendously good
focus on the registrar security bit so
you may have have a very good secured
network but in the end your domain name
is controlled by a very weak password
and this has been exacerbated that the
original and often most important domain
name for a company has been registered
by the founder originally in the early
days of the company when there was no
security department so the password
might be as strong as password one two
three and this is of course the ton of
pain where people's domain names have
been moved away from them
administratively and then error
had to have a fight to get them moved
back to themselves so I would say the
DNS has been attacked more
administrative lead and technically
oddly enough what would you call that
type of attack I think they do call it a
well they call it for example a
registrar hijack okay and there I think
in the US the and CSC created a special
name for it
which I don't know right now but the key
insight here is that if you run your own
business
or if you are in charge of domain names
try to figure out for all your important
domain names who actually controls those
domain names and there and users pay
very special attention to the account
recovery capabilities because more often
than not the original founder registered
the domain name from a hotmail account
which is still around and maybe loon
compromised and then attacker can go to
the registrar's hey I lost my password
so that falls into the normal type of
social engineering yes yes so these are
normal attacks yes it is but but as but
it turns out that people pay a lot of
attention to all kinds of things and
then the most important part of all of
them which is the the password that
controls the whole domain name of the
company is single factor and super weak
and I would I would classify this as the
biggest risk to DNS right now yeah I
mean my Ritchie current flooding a
connection with EDP pockets are
unordered you know as much as you can
when you can just call up technical
support and say I forgot my password
yeah I forgot yeah well actually if you
look at most big banks and if you look
at Google for example most of the really
big privacy aware companies have become
their own registrar because they decided
it was just too scary to hook all their
security to a company that has less
security skills than they do themselves
so in the Netherlands every bank is
their own registrar because that made
them able to have a direct connection to
the total people and not have someone
else sitting in between just compared to
the DNS hijacking you said it's not very
common but I just want to understand
when it's flooded with packets because
you previously explained that Tina says
UDP and they're not ordered they can
just sit and it will just confuse it at
some point and think oh that must be my
reply that's what you mean yeah okay
yeah that that's the that's the trick
and it used to be very easy to do that
you had to figure out only this this ID
field this 16 bit ID field and that was
trivial to do that was really simple
people could do it in two seconds is it
something you should be worried about
today
no because an RFC was written actually I
wrote it that said well actually we
don't need to just a random ID field we
also need a random source port and with
the fully random source port you just
suddenly went from 16-bit security to
32-bit security which is still not
luxurious but it turns out that if you
try to spoof 4 billion packets the
people do tend to notice ok can I move
us on to amplification attacks yeah oh
yeah sure oh boy yeah amplification
attacks with so many IOT devices I guess
is still out there
yeah it is still out there and actually
that at times it becomes huge so the
whole idea there is that you take a
device that does not have that much
bandwidth and you make it send a
thousand small DNS queries per second
which is maybe all you can get out of
this this small device and then you but
the queries you send out are designed to
create huge answers so you send out
these thousand small queries per second
and these small queries generate
gigantic answers of maybe 2 kilobytes
each and then suddenly you created from
your bandwidth limited device you just
created the 20 megabits per second
attack which of course don't know a lot
unless you have thousands of devices
again and from time to time and that the
trick is then to send out a query from a
fake IP address and then what happens is
your answer goes out from this fake IP
address and then the response goes to
that real IP address and if you've
picked your address right you can you
can ya send out a limited number of
questions from fake IP addresses and
then
flood the real IP address with great
force and from time to time last year
late 2019 someone decided to attack the
power DNS name servers this way and we
have no idea why we have no idea why
someone did it but it's it's it's still
big and and the the practical upshot of
this is that you should be yeah you
should monitor your name servers that's
really the only you can rate limit them
so modern DNS software is able to rate
limit itself that has its own challenges
but your your I performance name server
might be part of a high performance
botnet without you knowing it that would
be a public name so every wouldn't it
yes these are public name servers and we
we saw it as a bit of an interesting a
challenge to see well how well do we
deal with a few hundred megabits per
second of attack
I'll be your authority name server that
you've got yes as well as those were our
own our own corporate name servers and
what shall we we took this attack as an
opportunity to learn and we did learn a
lot I have to admit yeah you would
either you would have to read limit
yourself or be behind someone else's
denial of service scrubber something
like that but the DNS does attract some
yeah larger amounts of traffic than you
would expect maybe we've got a good
article on the I Triple E computer
science to society website on securing
DNS in the cloudy or that goes into that
so I've got a link in the show notes for
listeners to pick up on yeah I would
recommend everyone to read that link
because this is not a concern to you
until it happens yes how's everything
this is everything but it's this is
something that can go well for for a
decade and then suddenly you're like oh
this turns out that I have protected
everything in my network except this
okay can I move us on to poisoning
attacks yeah you could so that the art
DNS poisoning is that whenever you ask
DNS question it's not a simple question
and answer protocol so for example if
you ask the question
what's the IP address of power Deena's
dot-com to the root servers you don't
get back an IP address you get back the
name of other name servers where you
could ask this question and there's
another SEC a section that says well
hopefully here are the IP addresses of
the other name servers where you could
ask this question so whenever you
receive DNS answer you might find more
stuff in there than what you actually
asked for and this more stuff means that
a resolver has to take a very critical
look at what it received in the answer
to see which parts in there it should
actually be believing or using and back
in the really old days and you can still
read this in the original RFC standard
that is still in force today
RFC 1 0 3 4 and it will tell you that a
an authoritative server may helpfully
give you more uncertain than you asked
for and it recommends that you use those
answers and the problem there is that if
I ask for pardonnez com I might get an
answer for different records that I
never asked for and originally people
actually use those different answers and
stored them in the cache so I could just
send you a new IP address for a big bank
out at UK and resolvers would say oh
thank you that's very helpful and we'll
use that from now on yeah because yeah
because you're caching it you can tell
her what else you want yes yes so it's
the full name is actually cache
poisoning attacks where you try to put
stuff in the cache that is false and
that used to be possible by by attaching
additional answers to questions that
would then be accepted because the
standards as set as much said yeah you
should accept that and only in later
standards that is advice will be revoked
and said no no don't ever so I think
that so the original enforced DNS RFC is
one out of three four and that was fixed
only in two one eight two so so we have
advanced a little viruses before someone
says well maybe don't let everyone
poison your cache
these days it's a soft it's it's it's an
almost soft problem by the way except
that there are are still techniques by
which over days if you have days of time
you will still be able to perform cache
poisoning but you need days of hundreds
of megabits per second of DNS answers so
that the DNS hijacking and cache
poisoning
should that be discounted for my list or
is just something to keep an eye on it
is not the biggest the biggest worry
right now its if you care about this
stuff and I think you should care about
this this stuff of course is let's say
you have a name server and you see that
is receiving a gigabit per second of
traffic all day long that is that
someone would within a few days will be
able to cache to poison your name server
and that's the state of the art and and
that's something to watch out for but
it's known so in theory it's a risk in
practice we don't see a lot of it but
that's that's I mean the year is still
fresh you don't know is this something
developers need to worry about or is in
their upstream and now I did it's not
something you I'm trying to figure out
what the developer angle for that is but
one thing you you might want to look out
for is that if you have a a user
behavior if you have interested users
that could make your system perform DNS
lookups that would allow them to open a
window for this kind of cache poisoning
so it is not a harmless if interested
users can force you to do DNS lookups
and that's something maybe to look out
for yeah so imagine something user
facing where you've got a maybe
type-ahead search and you're not
sanitizing that properly and just
querying domains to check something yeah
that kind of stuff yeah or you're doing
reverse DNS lookups and your server side
exactly application type thing yeah or
if someone is as a form and they can
enter a URL in there and you try to
check the contents of that URL that that
those are things that we could make an
interested user perform yeah make your
server do DNS lookups yeah that might be
the nice features on
create a thumbnail image on some type of
profile or something where your system
is trying to go and look up that URL to
get some content yeah exactly and we
actually want one fun fun thing that we
do from time to time is you if you post
a URL on Twitter then name servers all
over the worlds will immediately start
trying to resolve that domain name so
and that's like hundreds of name servers
immediately do that and no matter what
you post on Twitter so you could use
that as a complication type thing yeah I
actually think there is a it does it
does teach you something about the world
and and who is who is monitoring these
domains and what name servers they are
using and where they are from there
there yeah there is an information leak
going on there and in general DNS will
leak your secrets because computers do
so many of these queries based on what
they see we found a very interesting
book I think it was in sublime editor
but I could be wrong where if you
highlighted a piece of text then the
editor would sometimes think it looked a
bit like a URL and would take your
highlighted text and perform a DNS
lookup with that highlighted text in
there that was a very scary information
leak because people do copy/paste
passwords a lot yeah exactly yeah and it
was fixed very quickly but it was it was
the kind of thing where we thought yeah
DNS is a window on the world and it will
it will just send out stuff random I
mean if you look at the the log file
most name servers do not local because
it's so much but if you look at the log
file of a name server you see the
craziest queries coming from people that
copy/paste at half a sentence and that
sentence ended on powerdine s.com and
then you get that whole sentence as a
DNS query it is a zoo yeah I think
there's some online tools to look at us
of things I've leaked out yeah
calling all developers there's no
telling what you can create when you
upgrade your data platform to inner
systems iris are you ready to build the
applications you want however you want
them are you ready to develop
applications faster than ever
collaborate build faster and deploy more
efficiently
tomorrow's next breakthroughs are
waiting for you today inner systems iris
data platform
ready set code start coding for free
visit inner systems calm / try to try
iris okay so so far we've spoken about
the attacks we've covered the overview
of DNS and the movement is quite they
kids
we've just got trusted all sorts of
things can leak out so where does that
lead us to you how can we think about
our privacy integrity the big one the
big e encryption is DNS completely
flawed at the moment or you know where
are we yeah so we do have DNS sack for
example DNS SEC adds integrity to DNS so
it means that you if you have an answer
you can validate that you got the right
answer
until you mean I as a software engineer
should volunteer or is that done before
me yeah that's the interesting bit
that's the really interesting bit the
software people we have not been able to
get the software people to do this so
what do I mean by that code applications
that use DNS have decided that they are
not going to validate DNS answers
so even browsers which are like very
good with security they will simply ask
a question of a name server and they
will trust the answer technically
speaking is entirely possible for a
browser to validate DNS answers using
DNS SEC and a surprising number of
domain names are now DNS SEC signed
browsers have have just decided here
we're not going to do it because we put
our trust in TLS certificates we think
those are better and who as the actually
signing so it's science and it is sort
of interesting what it signs
[Applause]
basically a piece of knowledge so if you
compare TLS for example or SSL and that
is what we call Transport Security so it
will sign whatever for you and you know
that the data you received is the data
you should have been receiving DNS SEC
works way differently and it works a lot
closer to how PGP or s/mime work in the
sense that DNS SEC actually signs the
final answer to your question so you get
an IP address for for party NASSCOM and
then there's a DNS X signature below it
and that actually signs death IP address
it does not sign the transmission of the
IP address it signs the actual name IP
address combination and that's now is
made it difficult to implement but now
that we have it it is there and
collectively all application developers
have said yeah whatever we're not going
to do it we're just gonna use whatever
our programming environment does when we
tell it to look up an IP address so like
the DNS library that yes the operating
systems using or yeah you could choose
to do it yourself can you yeah there are
very fine libraries that that allow you
to do it yourself and and then you could
verify the DNS X signature and it would
be more secure and and collectively
everyone and said yeah we're not doing
it it's really sad I I do understand it
somewhere because we have just put our
collective trust in TLS certificates
being correct but it's the same as you
know you're just having a a web forum
when you don't sanitize the inputs and
you don't do cross-site request forgery
checks and it should be the sort of
level with DNS if it's a critical
application yeah I do think there's a
little bit of difference there we can
honestly say that that as long as we
trust TLS certificates then the IP
address does not matter we can we can
just say look what every we could we can
use a 1.2.3.4 for all our communications
and just rely completely on the TLS
certificate checking to be correct and
why is the IP address yeah
basically it doesn't
the idea behind that is that you put all
your trust in the certificate for a
verification of HTTPS basically and if
you trust HTTPS to message integrity or
a transport integrity you don't no
longer care about the IP address because
the IP address is at that point is just
no longer mattering for your security
because the Transport has been as
integrity so you don't need to worry
about DNS sack if you're encrypting yeah
you could you could you could you could
take that you could take that phew and
that then actually not only could you
take that view that is the view that
everyone has taken where they say we
don't really we don't the IP address
doesn't matter because we just assume
it's fake already we get our security
from from verifying the TLS transport
and it's fine up to a point until you've
seen that there have been hijacks where
people hijack the DNS name briefly and
then were able to get themselves a whole
bunch of new TLS certificates based on
that brief hijack and that is the kind
of place where DNS SEC validation would
have held and the let's encrypt people
are now also doing that so that's nice
so there is a role for DNS SEC but right
now people are just not doing it yeah
there's a type of as a like a chicken
and egg scenario there where a lot of
companies to validate you own the domain
ask you to do what you discussed in the
introduction by hosting a tax record on
your website or your that's a name
record so if you've hijacked the record
you can then de get the certificate to
prove that if you're running DNS over
HTTP yeah it's yours
we actually did a show episode three
seven eight with Joshua Davies on
attacking securing private key
infrastructures PTI so if our listeners
can jump on there to see what you can do
to actually get that DNS SEC broken so
if you want integrity with our
encryption you've got DNS sack but if
you move DNS queries over to TLS or
HTTPS
you can kind of drop the inner sack with
the caveat that you've just explained so
so what does that bring us yeah where
does it bring us well I think the
Internet security is still right now
sell a web of cards or house of cards as
long as you can are able to take over
control of a domain name you can do a
lot of terrible things to people's
certificates and there are ways to pin
certificates and but they're not super
strong and I think the world would have
been a lot better if we had the in a sec
- well at least tighten up control of
that yeah that text record phenomenon
that you mentioned that if you are able
to manipulate a single text record on a
domain name that you're able to do
everything on it
from that point on so at the moment
we've got the privacy concerns as well
the wrapped up yeah
in all of this you want to take me
through what private Kent's privacy
concerns there are without DNS SEC or
encryption on the local network and to
praise network or public Wi-Fi just
briefly and then we can drill into how
we're addressing that and if that's the
right way yeah so it's very briefly you
should realize that DNS traffic really
tells you everything about a person so
if you look at if you only have access
to someone's DNS records she will be
able to tell where they live but phone
they have what brand of TV they have for
which streaming video services they use
where they live where they work what
they're but schools they go to what
sports teams they like DNS is per per
bit perhaps the most privacy sensitive
material on the internet right now
because it tells you it tells you which
hospitals you visits and everything so
it is very much worth it to protect your
DNS records because we don't want too
many people to have access to those and
is that because it has the domain name
that you're querying to map through to
an IP address yes exactly so if you only
have the DNS traffic of someone you will
see whatever they typed into their
browser and or whatever app they
launched or if they're if you have a
webcam or printer I mean if I
get the DNS traffic in my house I can
tell you exactly what printer I have and
what phones people have and when they
play and how is that is there some other
type of metadata in the query apart from
just the domain name that's that's it no
it's just a domain name
it's just domain name but if you look at
what what modern tools
what kind of DNS lookups they do the
whole name of my printer gets sent out
as a DNS query and and the Nintendo
switch in our house wakes up at night
and does DNS queries to see if there are
updates or not so that might be - like
Nintendo comm yeah or it goes through a
Nintendo switch update server comm I see
yeah I'll just try to understand how
your map yeah the query to the device
yeah no it's very it's very descriptive
of what's going on in your house and and
it is we did the small experiments power
DNS with a data set that we have which
is a pre pre gdpr that's a long time ago
but we try to figure out if we could
find ourselves in a this huge data set
and based on only a few things like
where someone lived and where they work
so you basically look at every one that
makes a connection to IMAP top power DNS
comm and something with the name of the
town in which they lived and we
immediately found our guy in this huge
data set because he was the only one
visiting power Dinah's calm and visiting
the name of that village so it is a very
descriptive and privacy sensitive thing
and it's very much worth protecting and
it's that for example if you have all
that information how do you map that
back to a person is it not just
arbitrary data at that point yeah so did
this get you to the point of what is
pseudonymity and and if you have a list
of IP addresses and domain names they
they visit this very quickly it becomes
d anonymized so if I look at myself I
radiate a pattern where I face it lots
of pardonnez dot-com related content I
have a few other projects and if you
would say give me all the IP addresses
that visit the following five web sites
that would always be me yeah so if
there's a
in FBI requests for birth for example
he's the chief architect of parody and
ass look for anything with pardon yes in
it you could go that way but the other
way around how you would need something
to look for really yeah you wouldn't
even need to know something about but
it's not that difficult if someone has a
Tesla and and and and I know that they
work at a certain company and I know the
name of the sports team that they like
that every step in that narrows it down
tremendously and and all these things
radiate outside from your radiates out
of your internet connection so with this
big list of leaking information to these
concerns go away if we switch to using
TNS over HTTP or tell us about the
problem certainly move because
encryption of course cannot this can it
cannot make the data go away because
this is Internet I mean you have to if
you make a connection to to a website
somehow someone will know that you made
a connection to that website it's almost
impossible to hide that you can only
choose which people do get access to
that data
yeah and if you were to profile your
office connection your home connection
there's still be X amount of traffic
coming from that connection between a
and 6 p.m. for example so they know
you're there
yeah oh that that's the other one that's
true that so that's the traffic data so
that's just the the fact that you are
using DNS queries hmm but the whole
discussion that's going on now is where
people say look Dean SEO and encrypt it
and that's that's bad and I am in full
agreement with that we should encrypt
DNS every place we can but the solution
that people have chosen for their to say
well right now most of your DNS traffic
is unencrypted between you and your
service providers or that might be sky
or that my PB T or it might be Plusnet
so they they can see what you are
visiting and the proposed solution is
then to encrypt tina's which is good and
then send it to a new third party and
they then get access to all your
browsing data
and and I'm that is a part where I said
I'm not that convinced that that
actually is progress because before we
had this highly regulated
telecommunications company at least here
in Europe and so the the
telecommunications company knows yeah
what sites you are visiting which is
okay yeah not happy about that but it is
the it's not pro progress if we then say
well from now on this American company
will know exactly what sites you are
visiting yeah your tell cause pretty
much heavy regulated by the government
yeah and it has upsides and downsides
that means is the third party knows
yeah telco typically here is very
regulated and and has to adhere to GDP
are or very GDP are like legislation and
that means they are in a bad place to
monetize your data it doesn't mean it's
impossible but it's a lot of hurdles in
place and it's gonna be very tricky to
just start selling people's traffic data
and if the proposal is and well we want
to encrypt your DNS but in order to
encrypt your DNS we're gonna send it to
I don't know Google or CloudFlare these
are far less regulated places well and
these are the current proposals the
original story was that yeah we have to
give it to CloudFlare because the big
internet service providers of the world
they are not working on encrypting their
DNS and the good news is that that has
changed with all the problem many of the
very largest Internet service providers
are now either offering or working on
offering fully encrypted DNS and with
that I don't see a lot of benefit
anymore of sending all my encrypted data
to a third party that I did not select
so if we just take a step back we've
been able to do DNS over TLS which is I
presume the natural step through a
protocol of a TLS and or encrypted and
we're done why we know or not in the
world actually so that we did this has
been standardized so that was an RFC a
standard that says this is how you do
DNS over TLS and then no one did it
nothing happened and why did nothing
happen for one thing as as we discussed
earlier people don't really see DNS as
dirty thing because they say well we're
not trusting DNS anyhow so we don't
really care and that was one reason this
is the lack of care the other reason is
that DNS of a TLS ruins of report eight
five three so that's the normal DNA
sport but then eight hundred hire and
port 853 is just simply blocked in most
environments you will not be able to
send out a query on port 853 from most
corporate networks because they yeah
everything is now everything blocks
these days except port 443 so HTTP is
the new TCP and so DNS of TLS didn't
take of one because people really didn't
care and secondly because most firewalls
just walked it
so why HTTP pass and a new protocol I
think you touched previously that poor
a53 is just not gonna be opened in the
real world and everything speaks 443 so
what is that protocol look like yeah so
so what they did when people got sort of
re-energized on this and they said we
need to do encrypted DNS they said we're
gonna make sure that no one can block
this it was a design goal it stated in
the first paragraph of the standard that
says we want to do dns that cannot be
blocked and and the best way of not
being able to block something is to move
it to generic HTTP queries and say hey
this is everyone has to allow port 443
anyhow so we're gonna use that so that
was one reason why they moved to Deana
so for HTTPS and the other reason was
that browser vendors were of course the
the big guns in this game they are very
good at HTTPS for them HTTPS is sort of
the basic units of functionality that
they work with so for them it was the
most natural thing in the world to say
hey we're gonna use port 443 and HTTPS
for everything because that's what we do
and originally even going back to your
question what does it look like
originally even their idea was to take
DNS and just sort of do away with it
reformat the DNS query as Jason and we
all love Jason is because you can you
can put everything in there and they
thought it would be good to sort of stop
doing this ridiculous DNS protocol and
and move to Jason and this got a pretty
long way even before it was realized
that that porting the whole Dinah's
semantics to Jason would actually be a
lot of work so then the decision was
made to turn DNS over HTTP literally
into that so you take a DNS query as
formatted normally so as it would have
been in 1983 and then take that normal
DNS query and put it in an HTTP
connection and that that's what it looks
like it's in that sense it is not
special so it'd be just like posting a
file content yeah it is actually it can
be a post of content it can also be a
get request both of their advantages and
disadvantages and it looks just like
normal HTTP traffic except that and the
queries are very small of course and
there are a lot of them so it does look
somewhat atypical from a network
connection because normally you will get
small query and then maybe a megabyte of
answer or whatever and here you get
small query and then also a small answer
coming back and and then a lot of those
and does this mean we don't need to
worry about any of the tack vectors that
we spoke about earlier or does it bring
a different sound actually it does
nothing really it helps you against the
attack fact or that that someone sitting
on your network would be able to tell
what sites you are visiting it also does
protect you against someone sitting
right next to you on your network and
trying to send you fake DNS answers so
let's say D D the attacker is in your
house or in your own network it would
protect you against your own network
like some type of malware or something
like that yeah or an evil let's say you
fake fake Wi-Fi access point or
something like that
and with these small pockets how fast is
a versus CDP yeah that's a very good so
the so it has has been found that that
with sufficient statistics you can argue
that it's not that DNS or HTTP is not
much slower but you do need quite some
statistics to make it happen
I would prefer to look at it in another
way a well performing traditional DNS or
a UDP name server will always be faster
than DNS over HTTPS and by some margin
even if you have ever make the
comparison between a not very well
maintained resolver and a very well
maintained TNS over HTTPS resolver then
you find that the very well maintained
DNS over HTTP resolver can in fact be as
fast or even a little bit little bit
faster in some cases then the not very
well maintained classic DNS resolver but
there is a significant overhead and from
the point of view of an ISP or network
operator can they prioritize this
traffic over another type of HTTP
traffic yeah
no no actually that would be extremely
difficult because I can i can't look
inside it no it looks just like normal
traffic and and in fact the the delay is
not so much due to congestion or other
things but simply by because it uses so
many more packets to get the same thing
done
so a typical DNS query response is
typically two packets classic DNS with
HTTP we've seen this take six packets or
more so that's like a factor of three
more so there is always going to be you
cannot prioritize yourself out of a
latency situation I guess you've already
got it implemented in power DNS yeah we
were actually so we we were sort of
really early with that and there's a
slight paradox in there that we've been
arguing heavily against sending DNS to
we have third parties mostly in the u.s.
because originally the idea was just
that we would start sending all our DNS
to to Google and CloudFlare and we
thought I was a terrible
terrible idea for the autonomy of our
networks and our privacy but many
people's then started fighting DNS over
HTTP and we thought that was misguided
we said no it's not the protocol that's
doing anything wrong it's what people do
with it
so we then shifted to making sure that
anyone could start doing encrypted DNS
that all the large service providers of
this world would be able to offer their
own encrypted DNS because encrypted DNS
is good so that's why we came out early
with these capabilities and have now
also been able to scale them up scale
them up for use in really large scale
networks with tens of millions of people
on there so while we decry the move of
DNS to less regulated third parties we
were very enthusiastic about making sure
that the protocol was easily implemented
well you've pretty much squashed my last
few questions in that section without us
really good efficient so if it's so
perfect what problems are there still to
work out yeah one of the issues with one
of the fun things and you put it the
other way around about classic DNS is
that because every query is just a
single packet that means that browsers
could just send out 25 queries and wait
for answers to come in and some answers
more might come in earlier something
might come later so for example if you
send two questions for the ipv4 and ipv6
address the ipv6 answer might come in
earlier sometimes the ipv4 answer might
come in earlier and a browser can just
simply use the first answer that comes
in if you send your queries over DNS
over HTTP that is actually a connection
based protocol and being a connection
based protocol means that if the first
question has not arrived correctly over
at the resolver the second question will
also not have arrived correctly the
second question can only be processed
once the first question has arrived and
it is called head-of-line blocking and
this is a well acknowledged issue in DNS
over HTTP and for this reason there are
now valiant attempts
I'm going to move HTTP paradoxically
again from TCP to a UDP based protocol
called quick qu I see this quic protocol
then brings the sort of out of order
benefits of UDP to HTTPS and that is a
big ongoing effort right now but it's
it's turning out to be the hard work
this isn't part of the HTTP to spec no
this is actually part of the HTTP 3 spec
because it turned out that HTTP HTTP 2
for all its glories did ship with the
head of line blocking issue that that
you just get when you use TCP so in that
way DNS of HTTP is actually currently a
step backwards in terms of sending out
parallel queries and operating on less
than perfect networks because this is
all about packet loss by the way I had
to just to clarify a single drop packets
will now cause DNS over HTTP to come to
a standstill
given all the intelligent people dealing
with us use a given loss
how did RFC 844 get out yeah I think but
I think the best answer to that is that
many of the people involved live in the
US and in the US the privacy situation
from service providers is just dire they
will they will sell all your data all
the time and from that perspective there
they argued we need to do something that
cannot be blocked by Verizon and the
only thing that they could come up with
that could not be blocked by Verizon was
deenis of HTTPS and given the background
that we have to do something and this is
something then you could end up with the
Dinah's over HTTPS RFC and then you can
of course have the privacy worries where
you say well look if we now start
sending our dns to another third party
Mabel maybe they will also sell our data
and then they said no we're going to
sign really
good contracts with those people where
they promise not to sell our data and
and then they arrived at the sort of
Nirvana for them where they said well
we've solved the Verizon selling all our
data problem and we have a contract that
says that this new third party will not
sell all our data and presto we're done
we achieved something great and from the
US perspective I can understand where
they are coming from what what benefits
do you see I've come out of this apart
from Tina's be encrypted well well that
is of course just a major benefit Dena's
BFF that we shouldn't overlook that one
if anything else has come out of it
it has been the importance of DNS and
and indeed the raising of awareness of
how little we are actually doing in
protecting it and looking at it so there
it is certainly on everyone's radar and
and DNS has always been sort of under
under appreciated and they're maintained
sitting quite uncomfortably between a
networking and application departments
in many organizations their DNS doesn't
live anywhere there is no team that says
we own DNS it sort of yeah it's not
quite the network it's not quite the
application in many service providers it
also doesn't live anywhere and this has
really put DNS on the map so I would say
that that that maybe beyond the very
important part of encrypting DNS the
biggest benefit may have been putting
DNS on people's radar okay thank you
and we'd like to wrap up the show now
obviously DNS is extremely important for
us all but if there is one thing that a
software engineer should remember from
our show
why do you recommend not to be it's a
tough one I always ask this type of
question at the end yeah I know it's a
good it's a good it's a very good thing
that you asked this monitor it that's
really I realized that this is not quite
the the software this from the software
developer standpoint but when Tina's
breaks everything will break so it is it
is worth an
a little bit more diagnostics to it and
maybe being a little bit more aware of
what happens and as one concrete example
that you could think about DNS if you
have long lift applications the actual
DNS answer that you got at the startup
of the application that you cached from
weeks ago may no longer be the actual
right IP address DNS is more dynamic
than it used to be and we still see many
applications that do a DNS lookup at the
very beginning of what they do and for
example to find the IP address of the
the database and then it will stick with
that address for the next five years
yeah we see that in the telco and the
telco world where you're using voice
over IP and you've done a lookup at the
start of switching on the phone system
yeah yeah and then obviously you're
using DNS for that some of us other
features to do with a little bouncing
and things the IP address has changed
because down so yeah that's that's
exactly what you just said okay yeah
well Deb would be my one thing okay and
normally when we're doing connection
based programming it's a great practice
to have some type of timeout to make
sure it's just not sitting there forever
is there something similar you can do
with with DNS to check would that be to
look for DNS SEC or just if you don't
get an answer within a certain time
we've ours are handled by the libraries
you use yeah it's typically actually
it's a good question it's typically
handled by the libraries that you use
and very often you also have no control
over it
so yes it's quite not something I see
exposed no and actually it should be
because you cannot just a native DNS
lookup might take as much as ten seconds
and you would only hear about it failing
maybe after ten seconds and that can be
a big big downer for any kind of
performance or failover to a secondary
thing but still there's there is no
solution for it because a bonafide DNS
query can actually just take six seconds
to complete there are important domain
names famous one was in the nature comm
the the famous science journal and they
had such a convoluted DNS setup that
if your name server was not already
aware about nature.com it could easily
take like 12 seconds to resolve the
nature.com IP address and and subsequent
lookups would be very fast because it
would have all the related data in the
cache already but there is no guarantee
that you will get a DNS answer within
any reasonable amount of time which is
which is actually one reason why in some
of our stuff we personally do not use
DNS because we were like yeah I don't
know what when I'm gonna get an answer
yeah maybe that's the take-home from
today is to be conscious that DNS can
take a while and it's something you
should maybe bring into application yeah
and the other thing that that people
could maybe think about this and that's
is DNS records have a time to live and
this time to live is just assess you can
cache this answer for one minute or five
minutes or one hour or whatever and
these numbers are typically set
extremely low so even though there is no
chance of this IP address changing 60
times per hour
we still set the TTL record to 60
seconds because maybe one day we need it
and it turns out that if you take this
IP address and you give it a TTL of
half an hour or even an hour then
everyone using your stuff just gets
better performance and the downside is
that maybe one day you need to change
the IP address and it will now take an
hour before everyone notices but I have
news for you
even if you put TTL on one minute
and you change it after one minute not
everyone is using new IP address so if
there's one thing to look out for it's
ridiculously and needlessly low time to
live some 10s answers and if you upgrade
that to an hour or half an hour then
everything will just suddenly become
snappier for everyone thank you is there
anything I missed that you'd like to
mention
no no I think this was was well rounded
and we did not get bogged down too much
in well visited areas of the DNS over
HTTP discussion yeah I've linked into
the show your YouTube talk that you did
and now nog yeah yeah yeah that was a
LinkedIn poll vixy's one also
at Euro VST which is really good so
where can people find out more and
you've got two Twitter accounts I think
yeah I think that the DNS one is at
power DNS underscore bet and that that's
why I publish most of my DNS related
thing yeah that's where I follow you and
see most of your tweets yeah no that's
probably the best one for if you're
interested in DNS Axum well birth thank
you very much for coming on the show
it's been a real pleasure this is Gavin
Henry for software engineering radio
okay thank you very much thank you for
listening
developers take your marks it's time to
upgrade your data platform to enter
systems iris it's time to deliver
complex mission-critical applications in
the fastest route possible it's time to
use any data from any source it's time
to embed analytics and create
interactive user interfaces so what are
you waiting for
choose your language choose your tools
choose your environment collaborate
build faster and deploy more efficiently
done and done
tomorrow's next breakthroughs are
waiting for you today inner system's
iris Data Platform
the fastest way to build applications
ready set
code start coding for free visit inner
systems.com slash tried to try iris
thanks for listening to se radio an
educational program brought to you by
Archer police software magazine for more
about the podcast including other
episodes visit our website at SE - radio
net to provide feedback you can comment
on each episode on the website or reach
us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter or
through our slack channel at SC
radio.com you can also email us at team
@ SC - radio net this and all other
episodes of se radio is licensed under
Creative Commons license 2.5
thanks for listening